Hello everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
Today we're going to continue to learn about
multiple choice questions in section 3, which is
considered as the most difficult question in IELTS
listening tests.
In this lesson we are going to review
the format and key features of multiple choice
questions in the IELTS listening test part 3,
understand and apply effective steps to answer multiple
choice questions including reading and predicting question topics,
underlining keywords, tracking answer options, and taking effective
notes.
Recognize common mistakes such as not taking notes,
choosing answers based solely on keywords without context,
and missing important signposting words.
And finally, apply practical tips to improve accuracy
including comparing speakers opinions in tables, spotting paraphrases,
and eliminating distractions.
By the end of this lesson you'll feel
more confident to tackle multiple choice questions in
part 3 of the IELTS listening test.
So let's get started.
The steps for multiple choice questions in section
3 are not much different from those in
section 2.
There are only a few differences in the
pre and while listening.
Step 1.
Before listening you have to read questions to predict
the structure of a listening section.
In section 3 you'll hear a conversation between
two or three people, often between a student
and a teacher talking about academic topics.
Step 2.
You have to underline the keywords in the
questions and the options.
Underlining the keywords helps you to locate which
part the speakers are talking about.
Guys, pay attention to the keywords that help
you differentiate between the options.
Moreover, the keywords in the questions help you
realize whether you need to focus on a
person's response or an agreement between two people.
Step 3.
While listening please move your mouse cursor or
pen to the option being mentioned.
If the question asks you about a person's
opinion, you only have to focus on what
that person is saying.
You should take notes next to the option
because there will be distractors there.
For questions that require you to seek an
agreement between two people, you should draw a
table in which the number of columns corresponds
to the number of speakers.
Please note that the options might not come
in order as the information in the recording.
Step 4.
After listening you have to choose the correct
answer and never leave your answer sheet blank.
All right, now let's move to the practice
section.